<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Kamakshi Institute of Medical Science and Research</title>
    <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Kamakshi Institute of Medical Science and Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kmhinstitute.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>B.Sc.Medical Laboratory Technology </title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/laboratory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/laboratory/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation The Tamil Nadu Dr.M.G.R. Medical University
Laboratory The NABL Accredited Laboratory, Government of India
Objective The objective of this program is to conduct various diagnostic laboratory tests, analysis and provide vital information about the status of an individual’s health.
Career Options This course gives rise to a rather recent and attractive career option in the form of medical laboratory technologists who will have options to join as perform and analyze clinical biochemistry, hematology, immunology, microbiology tests, histopathology in India &amp;amp; abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.Sc.Radiography and Imaging Technology </title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiology-imaging-bachelors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiology-imaging-bachelors/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation The Tamil Nadu Dr.M.G.R. Medical University
Approval The course is approved by the Atomic Energy Regulatory Board, Government of India
Objective X-Ray, Mammography, CT-scan, MRI and Ultrasound imaging are employed to diagnose diseases of the human body. The objective of the program is to prepare technologists, who are professionally guided to use the above technology, including patient preparation. They will be trained clinically in handling patients including digital radiography, fluoroscopy, mammography, computed tomography (CT),ultrasound and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.Sc.Radiotherapy Technology </title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiotherapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiotherapy/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation The Tamil Nadu Dr.M.G.R. Medical University
Approval The course is approved by the Atomic Energy Regulatory Board, Government of India
Objective To impart skills and knowledge to the candidates to work in conjunction with the Radiation Oncology team of oncologists, Medical Physicists and other staff in the application of prescribed doses of ionizing radiation for the treatment of malignant diseases (Cancer). Practical training in the operation and handling of the radiotherapy treatment equipment’s are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Dialysis Technology</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/dialysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/dialysis/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Objective The student learns to function as a dialysis technician with proficient clinical skills with a basic understanding of nephrology care. Upon completion of the course the student is prepared to take the examination to be a certified dialysis technician. The student will learn basic patient care related to the nephrology patient, machine technology, water treatment, and dialyzer reprocessing and educational development. The student will learn to give safe and competent nephrology care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Hospital Documentation and Records Management Technology</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/documentation/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Objective  The objective of this program is to conduct various specialty document records, numerical analysis and provide statistical information about the status of an individual’s health. Individuals learn certain functions and procedures such as analyzing records, ensuring compliance with laws, making reports, and ensuring accuracy of data; to store and classify medical records. Students are trained to analyze data and determine the appropriateness of medical services that are given to patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Medical Laboratory Technology</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/laboratory-diploma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/laboratory-diploma/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Lab The NABL Accredited, Government of India
Objective The objective of this program is to conduct various diagnostic laboratory tests, analysis and provide vital information about the status of an individual’s health.
Career Options This course lays down the foundation for candidates who wish to progress their career in Medical laboratory technology. They will start their role as technicians and technical assistants who are entrusted with the responsibility to assist the senior technologists in blood banks, perform and analyze clinical bio-chemistry, hematology, immunology and microbiology tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Physiotherapy and Activity Therapy</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/physiotherapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/physiotherapy/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Objective  The two-year diploma Programme has been designed to produce skilled and qualified professionals capable of carrying out specific tasks to make the lives of patients better. Dealing with topics such as Physical Rehabilitation, Electrotherapy and other modes of helping patients regain physical mobility. Diploma in Physiotherapy aims to produce competent professionals capable of assisting specialists in different medical procedures. The course teaches students to maximize the performance of human movements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M.Sc. Radiography and Imaging Technology</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/masters-of-science/radiology-imaging-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/masters-of-science/radiology-imaging-masters/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation The Tamil Nadu Dr.M.G.R. Medical University
Approval The course is approved by the Atomic Energy Regulatory Board, Government of India
Objective To provide specialized training in Radiology and Imaging Technology and its application to create qualified manpower to handle modern radiological equipment’s with a successful carrier. They will be trained clinically in hand by patient including radiography, fluoroscopy, mammography, computer tomography, magnetic resonance imaging and ultrasound.
After successful completion of the M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Board of Examination - DNB Programs</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/dnb-programs/pg-diploma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/dnb-programs/pg-diploma/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Kamakshi Memorial Hospital Pvt Ltd is recognized by the National Board of Examinations, New Delhi for training Candidates in the following specialties
Diplomate of National Board DNB- Broad Specialty Post MBBS:  Family Medicine – 3 years Radio Diagnosis – 3 years Anesthesiology – 3 years  Post Diploma:  Family Medicine – 2 years Radio Diagnosis – 2 years Anesthesiology – 2 years  Diplomate of National Board DNB- Diploma Courses  DGO- Obstetrics and Gynecology – 2yrs DA – Anaethesiology – 2 Years DCH – Paediatric – 2 Years DMRD – Radio Diagnosis – 2 Years  Eligibility  MBBS with full registration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
