<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diplomas on Dr. Kamakshi Institute of Medical Science and Research</title>
    <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diplomas on Dr. Kamakshi Institute of Medical Science and Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Dialysis Technology</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/dialysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/dialysis/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Objective The student learns to function as a dialysis technician with proficient clinical skills with a basic understanding of nephrology care. Upon completion of the course the student is prepared to take the examination to be a certified dialysis technician. The student will learn basic patient care related to the nephrology patient, machine technology, water treatment, and dialyzer reprocessing and educational development. The student will learn to give safe and competent nephrology care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Hospital Documentation and Records Management Technology</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/documentation/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Objective  The objective of this program is to conduct various specialty document records, numerical analysis and provide statistical information about the status of an individual’s health. Individuals learn certain functions and procedures such as analyzing records, ensuring compliance with laws, making reports, and ensuring accuracy of data; to store and classify medical records. Students are trained to analyze data and determine the appropriateness of medical services that are given to patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Medical Laboratory Technology</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/laboratory-diploma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/laboratory-diploma/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Lab The NABL Accredited, Government of India
Objective The objective of this program is to conduct various diagnostic laboratory tests, analysis and provide vital information about the status of an individual’s health.
Career Options This course lays down the foundation for candidates who wish to progress their career in Medical laboratory technology. They will start their role as technicians and technical assistants who are entrusted with the responsibility to assist the senior technologists in blood banks, perform and analyze clinical bio-chemistry, hematology, immunology and microbiology tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diploma in Physiotherapy and Activity Therapy</title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/physiotherapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/diploma/physiotherapy/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation Bharat Sevak Samaj, New Delhi
Objective  The two-year diploma Programme has been designed to produce skilled and qualified professionals capable of carrying out specific tasks to make the lives of patients better. Dealing with topics such as Physical Rehabilitation, Electrotherapy and other modes of helping patients regain physical mobility. Diploma in Physiotherapy aims to produce competent professionals capable of assisting specialists in different medical procedures. The course teaches students to maximize the performance of human movements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
