<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bachelors-of-sciences on Dr. Kamakshi Institute of Medical Science and Research</title>
    <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bachelors-of-sciences on Dr. Kamakshi Institute of Medical Science and Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>B.Sc.Medical Laboratory Technology </title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/laboratory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/laboratory/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation The Tamil Nadu Dr.M.G.R. Medical University
Laboratory The NABL Accredited Laboratory, Government of India
Objective The objective of this program is to conduct various diagnostic laboratory tests, analysis and provide vital information about the status of an individual’s health.
Career Options This course gives rise to a rather recent and attractive career option in the form of medical laboratory technologists who will have options to join as perform and analyze clinical biochemistry, hematology, immunology, microbiology tests, histopathology in India &amp;amp; abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.Sc.Radiography and Imaging Technology </title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiology-imaging-bachelors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiology-imaging-bachelors/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation The Tamil Nadu Dr.M.G.R. Medical University
Approval The course is approved by the Atomic Energy Regulatory Board, Government of India
Objective X-Ray, Mammography, CT-scan, MRI and Ultrasound imaging are employed to diagnose diseases of the human body. The objective of the program is to prepare technologists, who are professionally guided to use the above technology, including patient preparation. They will be trained clinically in handling patients including digital radiography, fluoroscopy, mammography, computed tomography (CT),ultrasound and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.Sc.Radiotherapy Technology </title>
      <link>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiotherapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmhinstitute.com/bachelors-of-science/radiotherapy/</guid>
      <description>Affiliation The Tamil Nadu Dr.M.G.R. Medical University
Approval The course is approved by the Atomic Energy Regulatory Board, Government of India
Objective To impart skills and knowledge to the candidates to work in conjunction with the Radiation Oncology team of oncologists, Medical Physicists and other staff in the application of prescribed doses of ionizing radiation for the treatment of malignant diseases (Cancer). Practical training in the operation and handling of the radiotherapy treatment equipment’s are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
